

Jhoni Ananta Sitepu

Bumi Marina Emas Barat, Kota Surabaya, Jawa Timur | (62)81226030023| jhoniananta@gmail.com| www.linkedin.com/in/jhonisitepu | https://jhoniananta.com/

PROFILE

I am an undergraduate in Information Systems who is highly organized with a strong passion for front-end development. I actively work on various projects, both in organizational settings and personal initiatives, and conduct research at my campus to continuously develop my knowledge and skills. As a front-end developer, I love tinkering with code and giving websites that extra "magic touch" to make them visually appealing, while also focusing on delivering a great user experience. I am a disciplined, active, and responsible worker, with a passion for carrying out organizational activities and social work to further improve myself and strive to become the best version of me.

EDUCATION

Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember - Surabaya, Indonesia

Information Systems: GPA (3,80)

August 2022 - Now

- Actively involved in research projects at campus, exploring innovative solutions in technology.
- Frequently contribute to website development projects especially frontend stuff for various campus committees.
- Regularly participate in organizational activities to enhance my soft skills and project management abilities.

SKILLS

Soft Skill: Teamwork, Public Speaking, Critical Thinking, Leadership, Quick Learner, and Networking. **Hard skill**: Frontend Web, Data Analytic, Machine Learning.

Tools: Python, Java, Javascript, Typescript, React JS, Next.Js, and Laravel.

RELATED EXPERIENCES

Information Systems Expo (ISE!) 2024 – Surabaya, Indonesia

Lead of Front End Developer

July 2024 - November 2024

- Responsible for leading a team of 13 frontend developers and actively doing quality assurance of the code
- Conducted bi-weekly design reviews for the work of 2 junior developers, providing constructive feedback and guidance to align their code with established principles
- Collaborated closely with the 20 developers to integrate the website's UI/UX and back-end components, and helped ensure that the website functions smoothly and efficiently
- Utilized Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, and React.js to develop the frontend of the project

Basic Programming Lecturer Assistant – Surabaya, Indonesia

Basic Programming Lecturer Assistant

February 2024 - August 2024

- Responsible for assisting an cohort for Information Student batch 2023 on the basic programming course
- Deliver and help the student to know and learn programming through Java programming language

Petroleum Integrated Days (Petrolida) ITS 2023 - Surabaya, Indonesia

Staff of Front End Developer

September 2023 - March 2024

- Responsible for making some of pages on Petrolida Website using Next is
- Deliver website slicing from UI/UX on the website
- Fetch and consume the API that backend provide to managing data flow on the website
- Utilized Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, and React.js to develop the frontend of the project.

Information Systems Expo (ISE!) 2023 – Surabaya, Indonesia

Staff of Front End Developer

March 2023 - November 2023

- Responsible for making some of pages on ISE Website using laravel tech stack
- Deliver website slicing from UI/UX on the website
- Communicate about problem or bug that happens on the website
- Utilized Laravel, Tailwind CSS, and PHP to develop the frontend of the project

ORGANIZATION EXPERIENCES

PMK ITS 2023 – Surabaya

Staff of logistic PKMBK ITS 2023

April 2023 - November 2023

- Contribute as a staff of logistic that manage equipment, sound, and transportation of that event
- Responsible for gathering, managing, and evaluating all the needs from every division
- Doing social activities went to orphanage and be close to each kid on that orphanage

PMK ITS 2024 – Surabaya

Steering Committee of logistic PKMBK ITS 2024

March 2024 - Now

- Create and design Grand Design of PKMBK ITS 2024 with other steering committee
- Designing the values that will be take and implements on staff of PKMBK ITS 2024
- Supervise and monitor staff and give evaluation when something went off.

Technology Department HMSI ITS 2024 – Surabaya

Staff of Technology Department HMSI ITS 2024

March 2024 - Now

- Became PIC of Tutorial Pemrograman, an event that is held to help students of information systems ITS to improve their skills at website making, and reach about 40 people to participate in this event.
- Managed a team of 12 people to hold a Tutorial Pemrograman Event.
- Create some pages of external website of HMSI ITS using wordpress, in: https://arek.its.ac.id/hmsi/profile/

COURSE AND TRAINING

- TEFL ITS| Score 503
 - Sertifikat TEFL ITS.pdf
- Introduction to SAP S/4HANA with GBI 4.2
 - SERTIFIKAT SAP Jhoni Ananta Sitepu.pdf
- Basic Frontend programming program from Dicoding:
 - Belajar Dasar Pemrograman Web dicoding Jhoni.pdf
- Data Science Academy ISE! 2022:
 - Sertifikat Data Science Academy ISE! 2022_Jhoni Ananta Sitepu.pdf
- Basic machine learning from Dicoding:
 - Basic machine learning dicoding Jhoni Ananta Sitepu.pdf

ACHIEVEMENT AND PROJECT

- ISCOM Scientific papers 3rd Winner 2023, with title "PENGGUNAAN TEKNOLOGI AUGMENTED REALITY DALAM SISTEM INFORMASI PARIWISATA UNTUK MENINGKATKAN PENGALAMAN PENGUNJUNG PADA ATRAKSI WISATA"
 ☑ Jhoni Ananta Sitepu ISCOM Juara 3.pdf
- Publish a journal with title: "Analisis Aplikasi Augmented Reality dalam Bidang Pariwisata Terhadap keamanan Privasi Data" which can be access at: <u>Analisis Aplikasi</u> <u>Augmented Reality dalam Bidang Pariwisata Terhadap Keamanan Privasi Data | Jurnal Kendali Teknik dan Sains</u>
- Publish a journal about Agile Scrum and developed an website that use AI for the content, with title: "PENERAPAN METODOLOGI AGILE SCRUM DALAM PENGEMBANGAN SITUS WEB AUTOMATEES UNTUK PEMBUATAN DESAIN KAOS BERBASIS AI" which can be access at: Penerapan Metodologi Agile Scrum dalam Pengembangan Situs Web AutomaTEEs untuk Pembuatan Desain Kaos Berbasis AI
- Founded Program at PKM-K 2024 an act as CTO in developing the Website in "Petsaurus: Aplikasi Pet Service sebagai Pelayanan Kebutuhan dan Kesehatan Hewan Peliharaan dengan Akses Chatbot 24 Jam"